MARTHA ZIMMERMAN

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/martha-zimmerman/

martha.zimmerman.j@gmail.com

903.388.3292

Adept in building and implementing processes in startup environment. Responsible for employee life-cycle and recruiting for SaaS Company along with six years experience in leadership, curriculum design, and training a variety of ages. Excels in challenging environments while offering motivation and supplying solutions. Supports colleagues and performs above and beyond duties assigned.

EXPERIENCE

Employee Success Manager/Business Advisor

GoodLooking Company Austin, TX 04.2018 - 09.2019

- Built/implemented numerous employee processes
- Recruited for all openings from job campaign to hire
- Managed/cultivated employee benefit programs
- Accounts Payable
- Accounts Receivable
- Responsible for all office manager duties
- CRM

High School English Teacher

Buffalo ISD Buffalo, TX 08.2016 - 02.2018

- Interpreted curriculum into engaging lessons
- Founded Game Club 15% of student population
- Sponsored Young National Novel Writing Month
- Assistant Director for multiple theatre productions
- 75% student improvement on state mandated exam

Math Teacher

Latexo ISD Latexo, TX 01.2015 - 06.2016

- Managed classes of 20-25 students
- Managed before and after-school functions
- Developed and operated gamified math tutoring
- Director of UIL One Act Play

Early Education Experience

Nacogdoches, TX 01.2012 - 12.2014

- Conducted instruction and observation
- Member of SFA's first Lead Forward Program
- Monitored students throughout the day
- Aided in the re-accreditation by (NAEYC)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Blogger

Beautiful Businesses Austin, TX 08.2019 - Present

- Reach out to owners of local businesses
- Coordinate and conduct interviews
- Write blog posts and use social media platforms to promote blog posts and engage with audience

EDUCATION

BS: Interdisciplinary Studies

SFASU Nacogdoches, TX 08/2010 - 12/2014

- President of SFA Texas State Teachers Association
 Student Chapter
- Dean's List: Spring 2011, Fall 2012, Spring 2013, Fall 2013, Spring 2014

SKILLS

- Creative and Technical Writing
- AudienceEngagement
- Social MediaManagement
- Google, Microsoft,& iWorks Suites
- Data analysis
- Data entry
- ProgressMonitoring
- Training andDevelopment
- Curriculum Design
- Editing
- Oral and Written communication
- Office Management
- Process Creation
- QuickBooks
- Confidentiality
- Empathetic
- Interviewing